Randall先生?
Mr. Randall?
他们到了
They're here.
5200万美元中超过600万 已经按超额配发权发行了
$52 million includes over $6 million already issued pursuant to the over-allotment option.
什么时候能完成?
When can we close?
还需经过两地的监管部门审批 多伦多和...
It would be subject to regulatory approval  in both toronto and--
我没问"怎么做" Oliver 我问的是"何时做完"
I didn't say,"how," oliver.I said,"when."
- 什么事? - 你确定这就是今后的方向 Roy?
- What - You sure this is a direction you want to go,roy?
- 这将使我们从能源服务转型到... - 你不觉得石油会涨价?
- This would move us from energy service into-- you don't think oil's going up?
当然会 问题是什么时候涨
Of course it's gonnago up.The question is when.
问题一直在于何时 如果 我们等所有人都看出投资价值
The question is always when,and if we wait until the deal makes senseto everyone else,
我们都会落在别人的后面
we're gonna be waitingin line behind everyonelse.
- 我只想说... - 你一贯为自己开脱的废话
- All I'm saying is-- the same cover-your-ass crap you always say.
我们得速战速决 我要走了
We're gonna have to wrap this up.I got to go.
- 你要去哪? - 上楼
- Where are you going? - Upstairs.
想法说服监管部门 我想在月底完结这事
Get the regulators on it.I want to close by the end of the month.
拜托 Roy 议程上还有十件事呢
Come on,roy.There are ten other itemson the agenda.
等到下周再说
Which will haveto wait until next week.
你不能把我们从办公室拖过来 开一半的会 然后把我们踢出去
You can't drag us all outof the office,get halfway through,and then just kick us out.
对 我可以
Yeah,I can.
抗生素治疗没有效果
the antibiotic treatment had no effect.
热度更高了 疼痛也加剧了 也就是说不是艰难梭菌
Both the fever and the painare getting worse,which means it's not clostridium difficile.
但你说这是唯一说得通的诊断
But you said that was the onlydiagnosis that made sense.
以前是
It was.
得送他去医院
We need to get himto a hospital.
爸爸?
dad?
我不想去
I don't want to go.
我知道 伙计 但也许我们得去
I know,buddy.But we may need to.
我会死吗?
Am I gonna die?
不 当然不会
No,of course not.
你怎么知道?
How do you know?
嗯 我就是知道
Well,I just do.
而且我一直都是对的 是不是?
And I'm always right,aren't I?
是
Yeah.
我想要House
I want house.
我理解 但我已经告诉你 House医生没空
I understand,but I told ou Dr. House isn't available.
- Foreman... - 打电话给他
- Dr.-- Call him.
告诉他我会派私人飞机去接他 不管他在哪个岛上...
Tell him I'll have a private jet pick him up from whatever island--
他没在度假
he isn't on vacation.
Foreman医生是我们这最好的医生之一
Dr. Foreman's one of our best doctors.
House被关起来了?
Is house in jail?
没 Foreman目前正与两名 House最资深的同事共事
No.Foreman is currently working with two of house's  most veteran associates.
去戒毒了?
Rehab?
不是
No.
Randall先生 你儿子将得到悉心照料
Mr. Randall,your son will be in good hands.
我儿子...
My son...
已经接受了悉心医治 但他还是快死了
has already been in good hands,and he's still dying.
我再也不要好医生了
I'm through dealing  with good.
我要最好的 我咨询过的所有人都说是House
I want the best and everyone I've asked says at's house.
所以除非他死了 昏迷了 或者疯了 否则我想他今天就来治我儿子
So unless he's dead,comatose,or insane,I want him treating my son today.
你可以凭着良心拒绝他
You could have said no in good conscience.
孩子依然是Foreman的病人 但他的父亲希望由你做诊断
the kid'll still  be foreman's patient,but his dad wants you making the decisions.
那他就不是我的病人
Then he's not my patient.
我做不了主 却要承担全部责任?
You want to give me none of the responsibility and all of the liability?
也就是说我要... 噢 真不错
Which means I get-- oh,cool.
别让他做出格的事
Don't let him do anything crazy.
他什么时候能拿回执照? 这样我们就不用再玩这游戏了
When is he getting his license back so we can stop playing this game?
也许拿不回来了 这游戏挺好玩
Maybe never.This game is fun.
你还要为这周Dibala总统的 M&M会议做准备(病发及病亡报告例会)
You also need to prepare president dibala's case for this week's morbidity and mortality conference.
噢 真不幸 我还拖着个指甲护理的预约没去呢
Ohh,unfortunately I'm overdue a mani-pedi appointment.
没说你 这是Foreman的部门
Not you.Foreman's department.
哦对 他有的是时间
Oh,right.Well,he's got all the time in the world.
我们弄错了 他死了 没什么好说的
We made the wrong call.He died.There's nothing to present.
显然引起了不少好奇心
It obviously garnered a lot of curiosity.
除了满足每个人无聊的好奇心 我们就没其他重要的事了?
And we don't have more important things to do than satisfy everyone's idle curiosity?
这不无聊
It's not idle.
我们如何抉择两种不同诊断
The question of how we deal with two possible diagnoses
而不同诊断的治疗方法是冲突的 这值得讨论
whose treatments are contraindicated is worth discussing.
腹部疼痛加剧加频 发热 脱水 腹泻 体重减轻
Abdominal pain increasing in severity equed frncy,fever,dehydration,diarrhea,weight loss.
母亲死于因I型糖尿病 引起的肾脏衰竭 已经排除了
Mom died from kidney failure caused by type one diabetes,which has been ruled out.
17个医生
17 doctors.
所有病因都被排除了
Everything's been  ruled out.
也就是说我们得重新排除
Which means we have to re-rule out.
重做病史询问和身体检查
Get a new history and physical.
除非这算出格 老大
Unless that's crazy,boss.
最近有没有出过国 或者参加过露营?
you been out of the country or on any recent camping trips?
没去过露营
No camping.
但一月份我们在蒙特利尔
But we were in montreal back in january.
我们去看了冰球全明星赛 庆祝我的生日
We went to see the nhl all-star game for my birthday.
真不错
Awesome.
House医生在哪?
Where's Dr. House?
在办公室里
In his office.
他更像个决策者 而非操作者
He's really more of a decider than a doer.
他决定让我们从头再来
He's decided we should  start over.
说不定之前的医生可能遗漏了什么
Never know what previous doctors may have missed.
比如这个
Like this.
按下去会不会感觉疼?
Does that hurt more when I push there?
- 没 - 是什么问题?
- Not really. - What is it
我不确定
I'm not sure.
规规矩矩 就这么简单
Just keep it clean,simple.
检测结果引起我们对初始诊断的怀疑 所以改主意了
We did a test that called into question our initial diagnosis,so we changed our mind.
如果他们问检测是怎么做的呢?
And if they ask how the test was done?
他们为什么要问? 只是常规检测
Why would they do that?It's a routine lab test.
常规检测可不包括从尸体上 偷血样来骗我做出错误治疗
Routine lab tests don't involve blood you stole from a corpse to trick me into giving the guy the wrong treatment.
对 如果你提起这事 肯定会招起一场热烈的
Yes,and if you brought that up,it'd certainly make for a lively debate
关于谋杀杀人犯的道德问题的辩论
about the morality of murdering murderers.
- 但基于你烧毁了唯一的证据 - 是为了给你做掩饰 而不是为我
- But since you burned the only evidence of that-- to cover for you,not me.
你是受到保护的
You're protected.
我们得二选一 没什么正误之分
The decision was a coin flip.There was no rig or wrong answer.
遗体已经安葬在八千英里外了 没人能证明什么
The body's underground,8,000 miles away.Nobody can prove anything.
屋子会挤满了人 不是因为 我们要二选一 不是因为病人的身份
That room will be filled,not because of the coin flip,not because of the patient,
而是因为House的部门搞砸了
but because house's department screwed up.
他们会像是装满鱼饵的 游泳池中的鲨鱼
They're gonna be like sharks in a chum-filled swimming pool
除非我在铁笼子里 否则我绝不会跳进去
and there's no way I'm jumping in unless I'm in a steel cage.
你想怎样?
So what do you want?
我要确定你把一切都掩盖好了
I want to know you have everything covered.
掩盖什么?
got what covered?
我们只是在回顾Dibala的案子
We're just reviewing the dibala case.
确保没遗漏什么
Making sure we didn't miss anything.
没遗漏 当然 除了害死他的病因之外
We didn't.Except of course the thing that killed him.
他便秘
he's constipated.
体检显示他的腹部有硬块 所以我重新照了X光
Physical revealed a mass in his abdomen,so I repeated the x-ray.
旧的没问题 新的一张显示 他的结肠几乎完全被塞满了
Old one was clean.New one shows that his colon's almost completely impacted.
阻塞可以解释疼痛
Obstruction would explain the pain.
你觉得是他们搞砸了旧的X光检查吗?
Think they justscrewed up the old x-ray?
不是
Nope.
先天性结肠功能异常?
Hirschsprung's?
这是一种先天性的结肠神经紊乱
It's a congenital disorder of the nerves in the colon.
在你儿子的年纪上很罕见 很多医生都会想不到
Very rare in a childyour S.'S age most doctors would neverthink of it.
- 是你想到的? - 是House的主意
- And yocame up with this? - It's house's idea.
我们需要做个钡灌肠 和活组织检查来确认
We need a barium enemaand biopsy to confirm.
让我猜猜
Let me guess.
味道很差 但会让我感觉好很多
It tastes really bad,but it's gonna make me feela lot better.
实际上 你用不着尝味道
Actually,you're notgonna taste it.
你该试着搜索一下"Misty May夺金记" (沙滩排球明星 夺得两届奥运金牌)
You should try searching for"misty may digs for gold.
记得加上引号
" Make sure you put itin quotes.
我在计划旅行
I'm making travel plans.
想离开这
Just need to get way.
给自己点独处的时间
Have some time to myself.
明白了吗?
You getting the hint?
就这样?
So that's it?
做完和Foreman之间的小实验了?
You're done with your littleexperiment with foreman?
那不是实验 是恋情
It wasn't an experiment.It was a relationship.
你也许想了解一下其中的区别
You may want to lookinto the difference.
真高兴你好转了 House
I'm glad you're better,house.
我其实挺喜欢为你工作的
I actually like dworking for you.
- 但我不会回来的 - 很好
- But I'm not coming back. - Good.
如果你回来 Foreman会试着挽回恋情 他就会放弃做头头
'Cause if you came back,foreman would tryand save the relationship and he'd give upbeing the boss.
你是来试图挽救 我和Foreman的恋情的?
Aryou here to try to savemy relationship with foreman?
当然不是 我是想挽回我和Foreman的关系
God no.Trying to save my relationship with foreman.
现在我就像科比 享受比赛 为所欲为
Right now I'm kobe playing the game I love however the hell I want.
Phil Jackson就得听其他人的抱怨 (洛杉矶湖人队教练)
Phil jackson has to listen to everyone else bitch about it.
尽情享受卡波圣卢卡斯 (墨西哥一著名旅游地)
Enjoy cabo.
我要去泰国
I'm going to thailand.
真的?
Really?
有意思
Interesting.
- 再见 House - 再见 13
- Good-bye,house.- Good-bye,thirteen.
上周 昨天 今天
***
难以置信 这月来他第一次 肚子不痛 而且有了食欲
***He's even hungry.
我饿坏了
I'm starving.
我们还在等活检结果 但这无疑是个好征兆
Still waiting for the biopsy results,but obviously it's a good sign.
你可别太心急
You're gonna want to take it slow.
想一顿就把失去的体重都吃回来
Don't try to regain all the lost weight in one meal.
- 怎么了? - 他的肚子摸着正常...但比以前大了
- What's wrong - ***
Jack 你觉得--Jack?
Jack,are you feeling--jack?
嘿 Jack 你没事吧?
Hey,jack,you okay?
右眼定住了 眼外直肌瘫痪
Right eye's fixed.Lateral rectus palsy.
他抽搐了
He's seizing.
5毫克安定
Need five milligrams of diazepam.
怎么了?
What's happening?
把这个垫头下 把灯关了
Put that on his head and turn off the lights.
- 我得查下视盘 - 心跳加快
- I need to see his optic disk. - Heart rate's elevated.
- 帮忙压住他的头 - 在压了
- Come on,come on,hold his head. - I'm trying.
- 慢! House人呢? - Randall先生 你得退后
- Wait!Where's house? - Mr. Randall,we need you to step back.
视盘肿胀 是颅内高压症
his optic disk is swollen.He's got intracranial hypertension.
静脉注射20毫克呋塞米
Furosemide.20 milligrams iv.
- 我们可以给他插管-- - 再注射5毫克安定
- We could intubate him-- need five more milligrams of diazepam.
别管监护仪了 注射500毫克苯妥英钠
Dc the monitors.Push 500 milligrams phenytoin.
- 不能一下注射这么多 - 得把颅压降下来 不然他会脑疝的
- We can't push that much. - We got to remove the pressure or his brain could herniate.
噢 上帝
Oh,my god.
50毫克苯妥英钠
50 milligrams of phenytoin.
去呼Chase 告诉他 我们手术室见
Page chase.Tell him to meet us in the O.R.
我们需要你的同意
We need your consent.
他怎么了?
What's happening to him?
颅内压过高
Pressure in his skull's too high.
如果不降下来 会对脑子造成损伤
If we don't reduce it,it could irrevocably damage his brain.
- 但他刚才还有说有笑 - 我们要钻孔降压
- But he was just talking.He was smiling. - We need to drill burr holes.
- 在他头上钻孔? - 苯妥英钠不起作用
- Drill into his head? - Phenytoin's not working.
麻醉他 注射3毫克泮库溴铵 然后插管并用过度换气疗法
Paralyze him.Three milligrams pancuronium.Then intubate and hyperventilate.
House在哪?
Where's house?
House不在 你是否同意手术?
House isn't here.Do we have your consent?Do we have your consent?
准备好了么? 1 2 3
Ready?One,two,three.
3毫克泮库溴铵
Three milligrams pancuronium.
你看监护仪 他还在抽搐
Look at the monitors.He's still seizing.
我们得马上动手
We need to do this now.
开始吧
Go.
电平显示抽搐停止了
Electrical seizure activity's stopped.
颅内压降下来了 来吧 继续
Intracranial pressure's declining.Come on.Keep going.
- 颅压降到了8 - 我通知他父亲
- Pressure's down to eight - I'll tell the dad.
怎么回事?
What happened?
我不知道
I have no idea.
抽搐停止了 硬脑膜下积液 细胞学检查没有异常
He hasn't had any more seizures,and cytological examination of the subdural fluid showed no abnormalities.
很少见直肠活检后会出现脑损伤的
Don't usually see brain damage after a rectal biopsy.
取活检后他还好好的
He was fine after the procedure.
没有头痛 精神状况也正常
No headaches.No mental status change.
- 跟我们无关 - 不只是脑子
- Wasn't anything we did. - It's not just his brain.
和硬脑膜一样 腹腔内积液在持续增加
He's continuing to build up fluid in his abdominal cavity as well as the dura.
我们已经采取分流治疗了
We've inserted shunts to drain it.
可能是某种系统性感染
Got to be some sort of systemic infection.
不可能 他过去一周都在静脉注射抗生素
Not after spending the last week getting pumped full of iv antibiotics.
你们觉着积液的形状有什么异样吗?
Notice anything odd about the shape of the fluid collection?
噢 天啊 这是...圣母玛利亚
Oh,god,it'S... the virgin mary.
边缘应该递缩 呈透镜状
The edge should be tapered,lens shaped.
除非...
Unless...
在积液形成前 硬脑膜已经和大脑分离了
the dural layer was already separated from the brain when the fluid started to build up.
做个硬脑膜活检 确认是否脑癌
Get a dural biopsy to confirm brain cancer.
观察得不错
Nice catch.
曼谷 799航班
Bangkok.Flight 799.
曼谷 听着真不错 去多久?
Bangkok.That sounds awesome.How long?
还没决定
Not sure yet.
幸好有个朋友住我家 帮忙照看我的狗
Luckily I havea friend who's staying at my place taking care of my dog.
他块头很大 经常做健身
He's really big,so he needs a lot of exercise.
Remy Hadley H-a-d-l-e-Y
Remy hadley.H-a-d-l-e-Y.
怎么 你以为我会 趁虚而入打劫你家?
What,you think I'm gonna rob the place?
不 当然没有
No,of course not.
你不是没看到 我有份正当工作
In case you haven't noticed,I have a job.
我很抱歉 我不认识你 不知你是好人还是坏人
Look,I'm sorry.I don't know you.You're either honest or dishonest.
- 为了安全起见-- - 最好把陌生人都看做坏人
- I figured the safer choice is-- is to treat a stranger like an ass.
你的做人原则真不赖...婊子
Nice way to live your life...bitch.
我说了我很抱歉
I said I'm sorry.
噢 喂
Oh,hello.
请问商务舱有没空位 我想用积分升级舱位
I was wondering if there were any business class seats open that I could use my miles to upgrade to.
虽然我不认识你 但我一开始便抱以信任
I don't know you,but I assumed I could trust you.
欢迎你坐上我的车
Welcomed you in my car.
好吧 你是圣人
Okay,you're a saint.
这不可能 我昨晚确认过了
That's impossible.I confirmed my reservation last night.
那再订一次
So rebook it.
显然是你搞错了 不是我的问题
Well,obviously it was a mistake on your end,not mine.
不 我正在去机场的路上
No,I'm on my way to the airport right now.
他们不相信你 对吧?
They didn't believe you,huh?
脑癌?
Brain cancer?
明早前就能知道了
We should know for sure by the morning.
我们的运气是越来越差了
Our luck just keeps getting worse,huh?
现在的治疗手段越来越有效
Treatment options are getting better every day.
目前还看不到肿瘤快 即使活检呈阳性 也只是早期
There's no visible mass,so even if the biopsy comes back positive,we've caught it early.
那照你说 这是好消息?
Oh,so you're telling me this is good news?
我的意思是 我们会尽力而为
I'm saying we will do whatever we can.
好吧
Right.
对不起
Sorry.
我要走了 Foreman让我帮忙准备 M&M会议的事
I got to go.Foreman needs more help with the m and m prep.
好吧 我做完活检后来帮忙
Okay,I'll come up and help after I finish the biopsy.
我们能搞定
We can handle it.
我们晚点回家见
I'll see you at home later.
如果你留下 我也不走
If you're here,I might as well be.
回家休息去吧
Go home.Get some rest.
我一回家就叫醒你
'Cause I'm gonna be waking you up as soon as I get home.
离我远点
Stay out of my life.
好吧
Okay.
我知道你取消了我的机位
I know you anceled my reservation.
你在咖啡馆偷看到我订机票
You obviously saw me log in when you were spying on me in the coffee shop.
我在和你聊天
I was talking to you.
偷看的是隔壁穿热裤的熟女
I was spying on the milf in the running shorts.
- 我不会回医疗小组的 - 我也不想你回来
- I'm not coming back on the team. - I don't want you back on the team.
我不想在Foreman手下 或身边工作
I cannot work for,with,or around foreman.
所以我不想你回来
Which is why I don't want you back on the team.
你不在时 他表现比以往都好
Now that you're out of the picture,he's better than ever,
也让我过的比以往都舒坦
which is gonna make me less miserable than ever,
所以咱俩一点也不在乎...
which is why neither of us gives a damn how,
你打算在巴哈马某小岛呆多长时间
when,or on what island in the bahamas you want to get from it all.
巴哈马?
The bahamas?
哥斯达黎加?
Costa rica?
我告诉你是泰国
I told you thailand.
我以为你骗我来着 因为如果 你告诉我实话 你也太白痴了
I assumed you were lying,because it would have been idiotic of you to tell me truth.
这是另一个我用不着你的原因
Yet another reason I have no use for you.
我们有麻烦了
we've got a problem.
Cameron送Dibala的血样去实验室时 特地要求对方做抗着丝点检测
When camer sent dibala's blood to the lab,she specifically asked for the anticentromere antibodies test.
又如何?
So?
他们送返来的回条 上有抗着丝点抗体
The printout they sent you included just the anticentromere antibodies,
但实验室还做了全血检查
but the lab also did a full blood panel.
我又不是白痴 我当然会 确保取血样的尸体血型一致
So,I'm not an idiot I obviously made sure the cadaver I got the sample from had the same blood type.
但显然你没有查胆固醇
You apparently didn't check his cholesterol.
相差多少?
How far off?
20%
20%.
Dibala并非死于胆固醇过高
dibala didn't die of high cholesterol.
怎会有人费神去比对两份报告?
Why would anyone even bother to compare the two reports?
和我这么做的原因一样
The same reason I did.
他们想挖出任何证明我们犯错的证据
Becae they're looking for anything we might have screwed up.
我们可以推说血检仪坏了
We could claim the blood analyzer broke.
不行 Cameron记录下她做血检时 仪器是校准的
We can't.Cameron documented that it was perfectly calibrated when she did the test.
就算数字有点出入 谁在乎?
So the numbers are off,it's weird.Who cares?
如果查到我们头上 就装出吃惊的样子
If it comes up,just act surprised like it's some irrelevasi curioty.
我不能这么做
I can't do this.
我不能用一个谎言 去掩盖另一个谎言
I can't go in there and stack lie upon lie.
你得想办法跟人解释
You've got to figure out a way to explain this.
我今早很想你
Missed you this morning.
对不起 我得早点过来 不想吵醒你
Yeah,sorry.I needed to get in early.I didn't want to wake you.
我以为你会叫醒我呢 你昨晚是这么说的
I thought you did want to wake me.At least that's what you said last night.
- 这儿没我事了 - 不 我拿到活检结果了
- I'm out of here. - No,no.I have the biopsy results.
不是癌症
It's not cancer.
这么多问题却一个查不出来
How can so much be wrong with nothing being wrong?
从什么时候开始 癌症也不算问题了?
Since when has cancer been considered nothing?
我刚说了 不是癌症 细胞形态分析正常
I just saidit's not cancer.The cell morphologies were all normal.
最近一次CT扫描也正常
And so are the most recent ct scans.
另一边厢 胃部腺癌会引起腹痛
On the other hand,andenocarcinoma of the stomach uld cause pain,
便秘 营养不良 继而引发癫痫
constipation,nutritional deficiencies.That could cause seizures.
而且CT上看不出来
And wouldn't show on a ct.
你的癌症诊断是对的 只是位置搞错了
You're right about the cancer,just wrong about the place.
如果你同意 请继续保持缄默
Continue to say nothing if you agree.
给他做胃镜 再做一组活检
Go scope h  Get another set of biopsies.
如果你带着两张飞往更棒的 度假胜地的机票去找她
I'd get canceling her ticket if you then showed up with two more to somewhere better.
- 你在说什么? - 我还能理解
- What are you talking about? - Or showed up at all.
但光破坏她的度假计划 也不能让她同意你的啊
But how does just ruining her plans get her to agree to yours?
你说13? 她要去哪?
You talking about thirteen? Where's she going?
这周哪儿也不去 多亏了你
Well,nowhere this week,thanks to you.
我没阻止她 我也不会阻止
I didn't stop her.I'm not gonna stop her.
我已经尽力挽留她了
I've already doneall I could.
现在我只能向前看了
Now all I can dois move on.
我想...我相信你
I  ink... I actually believe you.
如果你说的是真话 说明你比我设想的更理性--
If you're telling the truth,you're even more rational than I-- well,not more.
应该说 更明智
Then again,more sane.
你会是个好老板 老板
You're gonna be a good boss,boss.
我说了 什么问题也没有
I told you there's nothing wrong.
很明显有问题 况且我 也没逼着你去讨论这问题
There's obviously something wrong and I'm not even saying we need to talk about it right now.
我只是不明白你为什么急着否认
I just don't see why you have to deny it.
我没有
I'm not.
现在你又在否认自己否认问题了
Now you're denying you're enying.
不 我只是否认 有问题值得我去否认
No,I'm denying that there's anything to deny.
Robert 你办不到的 你什么也瞒不过我
Robert,you can't do this.You can't hide things from me.
关于Dibala的M&M会议出问题了
There's a problem with the dibala m and M.
他前后两次全血检查 的高密度脂蛋白数量不一致
The hdl numbers on one of his early blood panels don't match a later panel.
太奇怪了
That's weird.
是的
Yeah.
不是什么大问题
It's no big deal.
他的死因和胆固醇无关 但你知道
Cholesterol didn't have anything to do with his death,but,you know,
经历了被仁爱医院辞退 还有掉包13的药物实验
after being let go from mercy and then that thing with thirteen's drug trial,
Foreman不免神经兮兮 担心别人质疑他处理病例的能力
foreman's paranoid about about people questioning the way he handled the case.
这更说不通了 即便有问题 Foreman也没啥好担心的
That's ridiculous.If anything,foreman should be feeling secure.
他开始的诊断是正确的 是我们说服他换了疗法
He's the one who had the right diagnosis.We're the ones who talked him out of it.
我知道
I know.
不要告诉他我告诉你了 他不愿在人前示弱
Don't tell himI told you.He doesn't want to show any signs of weakness,
尤其现在House嚷嚷 要让他继续当老大
especially now that house is claiming he wants him to stay in charge.
好吧
All right.
那么说还是癌症? 只是在别的地方?
So it's still cancer? It's just somewhere else?
还有待确证 但这解释了所有症状
That's what we're looking for,but it would explain all the symptoms
以及所有检测和成像结果
and all the normal test and imaging studies.
取了粘膜和粘膜下层组织 正向幽门处移去
got biopsies of the mucosa and the submucosa.Moving towardsthe pylorus.
是我的错
It's my fault.
腺癌不是由饮食或环境因素引起的
Adenocarcinomasaren't caused by diet or environmentalfactors.
我24岁那年 继承了一家 1千万美元的管道燃气公司
I inherited a $10 million pipeline business when I was 24.
到我30岁那年 其价值超过了10亿美元
By the time I was 30,it was worth over a billion.
自此我做的超过50笔生意都所向披靡
Since then,I have been involved in over 50 deals that make that first one look like a loser.
我仿佛有了点石成金的能力
Everything I do,everything I touch turns to gold...
除了我的家庭 首先 是我的妻子
except my family.First,my wife.
现在是...我儿子
And now...my son.
这是我的错
This is my fault.
这是报应
It's karma.
这是不可能的
That's obviously ot true.
又开始抽搐了
He's seizing again.
把胃镜取出来
Get the scope out.
5毫克安定
Five milligrams diazepam.
- 颅内压多少? - 8
- How's the icp? - It'S...eight.
但是分流是畅通的 没问题
But the shunt's open and clear.
这不是颅内压的问题
This isn't intracranial pressure.
那这是什么玩意儿?
Then what the hell is it?
抽搐停止了 但他还没有恢复意识
seizures stopped,but he hasn't regained consciousness.
胃和食道无肿块
No sign of any masses in his stomach or esophageal lining
但硬膜下和腹膜下都在积水
and he's still accumulating subdural and peritoneal fluid.
每次我们打算观察积水打哪来 他就开始痉挛
And every time we look to see where it's coming from,he starts seizing.
你觉得是我们引起的吗?
You think we'resetting this off?
我觉得总有个原因引起
I think something is.
其中一个胃部活检显示出小动脉部分阻塞
One of his stomach biopsies shows an arteriole partially occluded.
但其他组织层没有反常 而且没有细胞炎症反应
but with no abnormality in the other layers and no evidence of a cellular inflammatory reaction.
这绝对不是癌症
It's definitely not cancer.
那一定是某种感染
Then it has to be some sort of infection.
我们已经排除了感染
We already ruled out infection.
那只是因为按照感染治疗后他恶化了
Only because he was treated for it and got worse.
- 听起来像个有说服力的原因 - 除非是抗药反应
- Seems like a sound reason.- Unless it's a drug-resistant strain.
抗什么药的反应?
Drug-resistant strain of what?
细菌培养 病毒血清学 抗核抗体 抗中性粒细胞胞质抗体结果都是阴性的
Bacterial cultures,viral serologies,A.N.A. And A.N.C.A.Were all negative.
一切都是阴性的 很明显我们忽略了什么
Everything's negative.We obviously missed something.
可能痉挛不是新症状 是旧症状
Maybe the seizures aren't a new symptom.They're an old one.
没有医生注意到这孩子抽搐吗?
No doctor noticed a thrashing kid?
腹型癫痫
Abdominal epilepsy.
痉挛可能比较像腹痛 直到蔓延到他的运动皮层.
The seizures would just ok like pain until it spread to his motor cortex.
这解释不了发烧
It wouldn't explain the fevers.
蛋白质营养不良可以造成发烧 每次进食都加重的胃部剧痛
Protein malnutrition can cause fevers and nothing causes malnutrition
导致营养不良
like excruciating stomach pain that getsorse every time you eat.
如果是我的主意的话我会更肯定的 但这是目前最好的
I'd be a lot more certainif it was my idea,but it's the best we got.
给他用Gabapentin(抗癫痫药)
Start him on gabapentin.
给他接上颅内脑电图不间断观察
Hook him up to an intracranial eeg for continuous monitoring.
- 我给他用了Statin (降胆固醇药) - 什么?
- I gave him statins. - What?
如果他们问到胆固醇的问题 就说我开了Statin 但忘了写在病历上
If they ask aboute cholesterol,just say I prescribeda statin and forgot to put itin the chart.
你这是拆了东墙补西墙
You want to solve a problem in the records by creating another problem in the records?
这就不算数据差错了 仅仅是记录遗漏罢了
It's not a problem with the records.It's a problemwith my record keeping.
没人能说我们错了
There's no way anyonecan prove me wrong.
你怎么拿到Statins?
How'd you get access to the statins?
你要让配药处的某个人 承认他记录也有遗漏吗?
You gonna get someonein the pharmacy to confess to yet anotherrecord-keeping p blem?
我看见药箱开着 就拿了一些
I saw an open cart.Just took it.
为什么你会偷一个能轻易得到的药?
Why would yousteal a drug you could justas easily ask for?
因为我在帮你逃脱责任
'Cause I'm tryingto get you off the hook.
一个不能自圆其说的故事只能让我越陷越深
A story that raises morequestions than it answers only puts the hook deeperdown my throat.
好了 我能应付
It's all right.I'll handle it.
怎样?
How?
实话实说
By telling the truth.
事实上我没有时间 我没这心情 而且我觉得没意义
The truth is I don't have the time,I'm not in the mood,and I don't see the point.
你不想参加"M&M"会议 因为你没心情?
You don't want to do the m and m because you're not in the mood?
这孩子命在旦夕 House还在拼命往我身上推责任
This kid is dying and I've got house trying to push all his responsibilities onto me.
这不是他的责任 这是你的
They're not his responsibilities.They're yours.
- 是你要负责的 - 我是想负责 但不想当傀儡
- You're the one who wanted to be in charge. - I wanted to be in charge,not a figurehead.
那就去这个会议 你全权负责
Then do the m and M.It's all yours.
你让我去被他们宰割? 为了什么?
You want me to get flogged?For what?
为一个不会再遇到的诊断疑难 做一个学术谈论?
So you can have an academic debate about a diagnostic dilemmano one's ever gonna face again?
到底发生了什么事?
What the hell'sgoing on here?
我只是不想参加这个会议
I just don't want to do the m and M.
- 成功了吗? - 差得远呢
- Did it work? - Not even close.
还好吗?
Everything okay?
只是在等看到底什么会出问题
Just waiting for whatever is about to go wrong.
13打电话来了
Thirteen called.
她有一个比腹型癫痫还好的解释吗?
She have a theory that makes more sense than abdominal epilepsy?
她说有人黑进了她的Email账号 取消了她的机票预订
She said someone hacked in her email account and canceled an airline reservation.
我猜是Foreman
I'm guessing foreman.
真的吗? 你怀疑是Foreman干的 不是我?
Really? You're accusing foreman,not me?
酷
Cool.
你真的想让Foreman继续负责这个团队?
You really want foreman to stay in charge of the team?
这样合理
Makes sense.
他喜欢权力 我喜欢谜题
He loves power,and I love puzzles.
你两个都喜欢
You love power and puzzles.
是的
True.
那是当我两个都拥有的时候
When I had them both.
不是Foreman干的
It wasn't foreman.
你怎么知道?
How do you know?
他说他向前看了
He said he's moved on.
你相信他吗?
And you believe him?
我相信他是这么以为的
I believe that he believes it.
换我上场了
Looks like it's time for me to get off the bench.
出什么事了?
What's up?
你是House医生吗?
Are you Dr. House?
我知道你是个超级粉丝
I understand you'rea big fan.
我会让人送一张签名照过去的
I'll have my guy send overa signed glossy.
脑电图显示没有发作间尖峰 这不是腹型癫痫
Continuous eeg shows no interictal spikes.It's not abdominal epilepsy.
你呼叫我就是告诉我不是吗?
You paged me to tell me what it's not?
我呼叫你是让你看这个
I paged you to show you this.
这我倒没料到
That I did not expect.
那这究竟意味着什么?
What the hell is that supposed to mean?
可恶 我就知道我应该呆在外面
Darn it.I knew I should have stayed outside.
幻想总比现实好
Fantasy's always much better than the reality.
你觉得这是开玩笑的吗?
You think this is a joke?
那是我儿子 他快死了 你们没一个有一点头绪
That's my son,he's dying,and not one of you seem to have the slightest clue hwy.
是的
I know.
这就是为什么它这么有趣
That's why it's so interesting.
发烧 胃痛 痉挛 腹膜和硬膜下积水 现在又是斑点
Fever,stomach pain,seizures,peritoneal and subdural fluid collection and now spots.
可能是对某种药的过敏反应
Could be an allergic reaction to one of his meds.
在他用药以后8小时突然发作吗?
That suddenly developed eight hours after he started the meds?
如果不是癌症 感染 那一定是自体免疫病
If it's not cancer infection,it has to be autoimmune.
全身狼疮加上中枢神经系统血管炎 可以解释红疹 发烧 腹水--
Systemic lupus complicated by a cns vasculitis would explain the rash,fever,ascites--
中枢神经系统血管炎会出现斜颈 还会伴随头疼
cns vasculitis would causea stiff neck along with a headache.
那应该在硬脑膜活检上看出来
And would've showed upon the dural biopsy.
结节性多动脉炎呢? 小孩子也可能患上
What about polyarteritisnodosa?It can occur in kids.
但多动脉炎不可能没有炎症
Except you can't have arteritis without inflammation.
好 你来想个更好的
Okay,you come up with something better.
继续
Go on.
皮肤活检结果有一些炎症 加上他的舒张压偏高
There was some inflammation in the skin biopsy,plus he's got elevated diastolic pressure.
只是有一点高 考虑到他目前的治疗状况 是完全可预见的
It's barely elevated,which you'd expect given the number of procedure she's undergone.
有一点总比没有一点强
Well,barely is more than not barely.
不该我决定
Not my decision.
但如果该我的话 我会说给他用强的松 再做一个睾丸活检
But if it was,I'd say start him on prednisone and get a testicular biopsy.
如果他真的有炎症的话 应该在那里
If he's gonna have any real inflammation,it'll be down there.
- Cameron和我会去做 - 为什么?
- Cameron and I will do it. - Why?
那是Chase的主意
It was chase's idea.
家属不会对第四组活检有什么好脸色 而你比较善于打圆场
Kid's father is not gonna be happy  about a fourth set of biopsies,and you've got a better rapport.
实际上是怎么回事?
What's reallygoing on here?
你要Chase帮你准备 M&M例会吗?
You need chase to help youover-prep for the m and m?
- 是的 - 那你就说出来 别像个孩子似的
- Yes. - Then say so.Don't be a child.
孩子的红疹在他的阴茎上也有吗?
Is it on his penis kid's rash?
是的 怎么了?
Yeah,why?
那就不太可能影响到小血管
Means it's most likely affecting the small blood vessels.
所以我们在所有活检上都没发现炎症
That's why we didn't see any inflammation on the biopsies.
这不是多动脉炎
It's not polyarteritis.
是恶性萎缩性丘疹病
It's degos disease.
我去吧
I'll do it.
你儿子得的是恶性萎缩性丘疹病
Your son has degos disease.
导致脑内微型血管 皮肤 胃肠道损坏 出血
Causes microblood vessels  in the brain,skin,gi tract to break down,ffclot o.
有时会在早期在阴茎上出现萎缩性丘疹
It sometimes manifests early on with atrophic papuleson the penis.
但你儿子的病 不知道为何 丘疹出现得晚很多
In your son's case,we don't know why,but they came much later.
怎样治疗呢?
What's the treatment?
没有治疗方法
There isn't one.
无药可治
It's incurable.
你错了
You're wrong.
你已经错了很多次
You've already been wrong a bunch of times.
我们复查了活检 绝对是恶性萎缩性丘疹病
We've rechecked the biopsies.It's definitely degos.
我很遗憾 但愿有什么我们能做的
I'm sorry.I wish there was something we could do.
还有多久?
How long?
没多久
Not much longer.
那是什么意思?
What does that mean?
最多一天
Day at the most.
好的 太好了
All right,great.
我们需要谈谈
We need to talk.
除非是生死攸关 要不然就得等等
Unless it's life odeath,it's gonna have to wait.
是关于Dibala总统
It's about dibala.
- 更正 除非是目前的生死攸关的事 - Foreman不能参加M&M例会
- Well,let me rephrase.Unless it's a current life-- foreman can't present the case at the m and M.
我知道你们很忙 但他得克服 抽出时间
I know you guys are busy,but he's just gonna have to suck it up and make the time.
- 不是时间的问题 - 那是什么?
- It's not the time. - Then what is it?
抗着丝点抗体实验
The anticontromere antibodies test.
那个实验让我们把诊断 从牙生菌病换成了硬皮病...
The test that caused us to change the treatment from blastomycosis to scleroderma...
- 它不是 - 不是什么?
- it wasn't-- wasn't what?
Cuddy医生?
Dr. Cuddy?
- 儿科重症监护病房需要你 - 谁?
- They need youin the pediatric icu. - Who's they?
我不知道 但我想他们是律师
I don't know.But I think they're lawyers.
如果你们搞砸了什么事情 那就全招了吧
If you guys screwed somethingup,just come clean.
不见得会很惨
It's not gonna be that bad.
恕我冒昧 你不知道现在关键的是什么
with all due respect,you don't know what's at stake here.
- 怎么了? - 你必须阻止他!
- What's going on? - You need to stop him!
他要毁了他的生活
He's about toruin his life.
说着像我的生活是你给的一样
Like you givea damn about my life.
Roy 他说的没错 不能借钱来购买 早就亏损的期权
Roy,he's right.You're borrowing money to buy options  that are already out of the money.
即使是你也承担不起这损失
Even you won't be ableto cover the losses.
算上你的房产 汽车 银行存款
Your house,cars,bank accounts.
- 你会失去一切的 - 他就是要这么做
- You'll lose everything. - that's the point.
这个亿万富翁觉得如果他破产了 上帝就会恩泽于他
The billionaire thinksthat the gods will treat him betterif he's broke.
- 我建议他把财产给我 - 世间肯定存在着某种平衡
- I suggested he give it to me. - there's got to be some sort of balance.
你不可能在生活的某个方面 占尽所有的好处
You can't haveall the good fortune in just one areaof your life.
这个世界不应该是这样
It's not how the worldis supposed to look.
谁告诉你这个世界应该是什么样子的?
Who said the world is supposed to work?
不能不计后果 把你的财产托管吧
Don't just wipe everything out.Put your assets in a trust.
- 捐了它 - 不能有任何回报
- Give it to a charity. - I can't get anything back.
- 他疯了 - 是不理智
- He's insane. - He's irrational.
和大多数人一样
So are most people.
不巧的是 他并没有疯
Unfortunately it doesn't makehim insane.
如果他签了字 他不仅是毁了自己的生活
If he signs that paper,he's not only gonna destroy his own life,
还有靠这公司养活的上千人的生活
but the lives of thousands of people who rely  on this company to make a living.
如果他疯了 我们会起诉这家医院...
If he is insane,we will sue this hospital--
Randall先生... 我知道你很烦恼
Mr. Randall... I know you're upset.
目前 你不应该做这样的决定
You shouldn't make a decisionlike this right now.
考虑一段时间
Give it some time.
我的儿子没有时间了
My son doesn'thave any time.
你的儿子是因为不治之症生命垂危 不是因为报应
Your son's dying from an incurable disease,not bad karma.
不
No.
他不会死
He's not dying.
他不会死 我不会让他死
It's not gonna happen.I'm not gonna let it.
Roy 求你了!
Roy,please!
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
我不能让他死
I can't let him die.
不是做好事就有好报 得失谁也无法控制
People don't get what they deserve.They just get what they get.
我们没法改变它
There's nothing any of us can do about it.
照此执行 不然我保证你们会一无所有
Deliver it or I'll make sure you end up the ones with nothing.
准备急救
Prepare for the first aid.
- 谢谢 - 不客气
- Thank you. - You're welcome.
为什么谢我?
For what?
谢谢你觉得 为了让我留下 我值得你做违法的事
For thinking I was worth breaking the law to keep around.
我就是那样的人 但我还是不知道你在说什么
That's just the way I am,but still don't know what you're talking about.
Cuddy让IT人员追踪了所有 登陆我邮箱的IP地址
Cuddy had I.T. Trace allthe I.P.Addresses who' logged into my email account.
发现两个地址
There were two.
我的和你的
Mine and yours.
- 很显然House觉得他需要你比... - 我早就问过House了
- Obviously house decided he needs you more than he's-- I already asked house.
那他就从来不撒谎
And he'd certainly never lie.
不是 他会撒谎 除非他想叫我走
No,he'd lie.Except he wants me gone.
而且他的撒谎技术比你高明多了
And he do a lot better job of lying than you just did.
真的? 这么明显吗?
Really?It was that bad?
其实还可以
No,actually.
但是这已经无关紧要了
But it doesn't matter anymore.
为什么这么做? 是因为House还是Foreman?
Why?Beuse of house or foreman?
你对他们都很重要 只是Foreman不是我最好的朋友
You're good for both of them,but foreman's not my best friend.
House不会有事的
House will be fine.
可能是
Maybe.
但是你在组里 他会更好
But with you on the team,he'd be better.
他需要一个...并不需要他的人在身边
He needs someone... who doesn't need him.
你是唯一个没有被卷入 变态的House旋涡的人
You're the only one he's never reallybeen able to suck into his crazy house vortex.
让他知道点分寸 他能自我反省
Keeps him grounded.His ego in check.
那你为什么不直接来找我?
Why didn't you justcome to me?
我觉得只有House来挽留你才会留下 我知道他到最后是会的
I figured you'd only stayif house asked and I knewhe would eventually.
再见 Wilson
Bye,wilson.
这是一份很好的工作
This is a great job.
可能现在更好了 因为House至少 试着认真与人交往
Maybe even better now that house is at least trying to have real relationshipswith people.
我是说"试着"
I said,"trying.
这无关紧要
" It doesn't matter.
你热爱的工作 对你无关紧要吗?
The job you love doesn't matter?
不要因为一次糟糕的分手 就统统抛弃
Don't throw it all away just because of a bad break-up.
再见 Wilson
Bye,wilson.
我都坦白了
I just confessed.
我告诉13 她的机票是我取消的
I told thirteen I was the onewho canceled the plane ticket.
- 为什么? - 为什么承认还是为什么这么做?
- Why? - You mean why did I confess or why did I do it?
我知道不是你干的 所以我问的是前者
I kn you didn't do it,so I guess the first.
你想让她留下是因为你要她回来 还是Foreman要她回来?
You want her to stay becauseyou want her back or because foreman does?
我何必关心Foreman要什么?
Why would I carewhat foreman wants?
因为你其实没有所有人想得那么混蛋
Because you're not as big a jerkas everyone thinks.
- 我是的 - 不 你不是
- Yes,I am. - No,you're not.
我刚刚抛空一万元股票 我知道它会暴跌因为
I just made a $10,000 short sale on a stock I know is gonna crash because of
我看见那个悲伤欲绝的父亲 在他儿子临死前干了什么
what I saw a grief-stricken dad doon his son's deathbed.
不 你没有
No,you didn'T.
我有的
Yes,I did.
你真是个混蛋
You are a jerk.
她犯了个错误
She's making a mistake.
所以你是为了她好?
So you did it for her?
- 她是个好医生 - 那你是为了自己好?
- She's a good doctor. - So you did it for you?
我不再是主管了
I'm not the one in charge anymore.
那你是为了Foreman好?
So you did itfor foreman?
她是个超级性感的 刚恢复单身的双性恋
She's a smoking hot,newly single bisexual.
你为啥就是不肯承认你希望她留下?
Why don't you just admit thatyou like having her around?
她对你很重要 你需要她
She's good for you.You need her.
因为我的心脏天生小三号 (引"圣诞怪杰"心脏小三号 喜欢破坏幸福)
Because I was born with a heart three sizes too small.
- 不 你没有 - 是的 我...
- No,you weren'T.- Yes,I--
怎么了?
what?
- 他还活着吗? - 是的
- He still alive? - yeah.
很好
Good.
给他用肝素 静脉推注免疫球蛋白
Start him on heparin and iv immunoglobulin.
治疗恶性萎缩性丘疹?
For degos?
心脏停搏并不是那种恶心的停搏
The cardiac arrest wasn't just a "everything goes to hell in a handbasket" arrest.
是冠脉病变 冠状动脉是大血管
It was a coronary event.Coronaries are large vessels.
也就是说 这不是恶性萎缩性丘疹
Mean's it can't be degos.
- 但是组织活检证实... - 阻塞的血管
- But the biopsies confirmed-- obstructed blood vessels.
恶性萎缩性丘疹 不可能导致血管阻塞
But they can't be obstructed because of degos.
是抗磷脂综合症状
Means it's primary antiphospholipid syndrome.
- 你确定? - 不确定
- You sure? - Nope.
但如果肝素和免疫球蛋白起效 我就能确定
But I will be if he respondsto the heparin and the immunoglobulin.
顺便 有人搞砸了你女朋友的事 她跑来找我 Cuddy还有Wilson
By the way,someone screwed over your girlfriend and she ran to me,uddy,and wilson.
所有人都找了 除了你
Everyone but you.
她还在乎你
She's not over you.
难说
Or she is.
你在哪儿找到的?
Where'd you find it?
找到什么?
Find what?
烟碱酸铬补充剂
The niacin boundchromium supplements.
就放在文件上面 你知道不?
It was right on top of th.File you don't know about it?
不知道 一晚上都在这儿
No.Been here all night.
Dibala之前的医生开 过量烟碱酸铬以提升他的高密度脂蛋白
One of dibala's previous docs was prescribing ultra high doses of niacin boundchromium to boost his hdl.
所以呢?
So?
所以我们就找到理由了
So it gives us somethingto point to.
我们可以解释高密度脂蛋白 大幅变化的原因
We can explain the wide variation between the hdl numbers.
我们就没事了
We're safe.
有救了
We're covered.
真不是你要来的资料?
You really didn't request the info?
不是
No.
很显然也不是你
And obviouslyyou didn't either.
也就是说...
Which means...
爬得高 摔得重 首席执行官一夜破产
***
成了
it worked.
是药物的效果
The medicine worked.
有效
It worked.
你怎么发现的?
How'd you find it?
那个肥硕的老黑人
Fat old black guy.
一看就知道为了控制胆固醇 他肯定用过点什么药
Knew he had to be taking something for his cholesterol.
那现在呢?
And what now?
我又不是老板
I'm not the  boss.
你不觉得该炒了我吗?
You don't think I should be fired?
为什么要炒了你?  我们再不会 医治种族灭绝主义的独裁者了
Why?I doubt we'll ever be treatinga genocidal dictator again.
当凶手比诊断误差要好
Better a murder than a miss.Agnosi
不管你想不想...
whether you want to bein charge or not... 
你现在是 也永远是老大
you are and youalways will be.
75岁的非洲男性突发大咯血 收入我院
75-year-old african man  presented to our hospital following  a rapid onset of hemoptysis.
发作前体健 无胸痛 发热 咳嗽和寒战...
He'd been fine prior to onset.No chest pain,fever,coughing,or chills...
("Sarah" By Ray LaMontagne)
***
* 初见时我们还是孩童 *
* when we first met we were kids *
* 我们无知而活泼 *
* we were wild we were restless *
* 时间流逝我历尽沧桑 *
* after a while I grew coarse *
* 我变冷酷变鲁莽*
* I grew cold I grew reckless *
* 我珍藏这段回忆 *
* I hold this memory *
* 把你牢牢抱紧 *
* hold you so close to me *
* 呢喃道我们会永远幸福 *
* whispered we'll be always happy *
* 现在我意识到 *
* now I see *
* 我曾经如此年轻如此胆怯 *
* just how young how scared I was *
* 双眼紧闭 *
* eyes closed tight *
* 在逆境中成长 *
* throwing punch after puncha t the world *
* Sarah *
* sarah *
* 是否还能一如往日 *
* is it ever gonna bethe same *
* Sarah *
* sarah *
* 是否还能一如往日 *
* is it ever gonnabe the same *